

curriculum vitae

Hägerstensvägen 175, 126 53 Stockholm, Sweden +46 70 092 30 27 • sasha.milic@mac.com

About Me

DATE OF BIRTH: October 8, 1975.

A motivated System Architect, Mobile & Design Team Leader, able to produce clean and maintainable code quickly. My development and leadership styles are quite similar. I like to keep things simple, stay agile and responsive, so I can meet requirements quickly. I tend to design and plan my way to avoid "big-bang" deliveries, preferring an incremental approach with an element of fail-fast. You can say that I am results-oriented software developer and research professional with sixteen years experience in both development and research positions.

Employment

FULL-TIME: OPENRATIO TECHNOLOGIES AB (2016-NOW)

My responsbility as Lead system architect & Head of Mobility department were to upgrade system, make product better in every way, lead the team, make shore company have constant delivery. Involved in all project and organization matters, UI/UX Design, product design, create unique iOS & Android architecture for this product. I were also involved in marketing strategy for expanding to other markets. www.openratio.com

NORNIX, AB (2015-NOW)

I held the position of system architect, iOS team leader and I were a figure in all project and organization matters. My key responsibilities were to organise iOS team, help them to improuve they knowledge and code for iOS. I put one very hard decision in time when new SWIFT language has lunched. It's to cut future coding in Objective-C and transfer to SWIFT. It was hard from begining. We did not have reuse code and libraries. www.nornix.se

SOFT DEVELOPMENT, D.O.O. (2006-2012)

Design, brand complete creation. Develop iOS client in Objective-C for enterprise download. Making of UI design and Storyboard preparing for developers only to ad underline logic. Worked in a team with c++ programmer, code animations of download client for casino and poker.

VODAFONE D2, GMBH (2003-2004)

I was managing external designers and studios and work with relevant internal stakeholders on a daily basis to develop product concepts and turn them into real life products—from sketch to tooling. Maintain and thoroughly ensure the implementation of Vodafone's global design philosophy and language, across all relevant products. www.vodafone.de

DEUS, D.O.O. (1993-1995)

Worked as young 3D modeler as a part of talented and growing team of architects and project managers! As 3D modeler, I worked very closely with texture painters and art director, to generate models that are suitable for TRADE Mall artwork. Later on this was very handy when worked in Augmented reality for iOS. I used vuforia sdk and implemented all combination that is avaible within framework.

PART-TIME: BRAINON, AB (2012-2014)

Working on independent projects in development and planning. The company is engaged in promotion of profitable educational project.



Hägerstensvägen 175, 126 53 Stockholm, Sweden +46 70 092 30 27 sasha.milic@mac.com

PART-TIME: APPLICATION-LAB, D.O.O. (2012-NOW)

Expand basic code from sHotels base and add some features regarding memory and optimisation of code. Work in a team with senior iOS developer. We are both searching and implementing cuting edge code to be able to acomplish perfection in simplicity. www.application-lab.com

COMIT GROUP, D.O.O. (2012-2014)

Worked on my own idea of Smart Hotel System. Build whole project and lead iOS team and strategy in coding application for iPhone and iPad. Code is done in Objective-C. Aprrouved from Apple first-time.

INDIVIDUAL PROJECTS: LiveFrameEdit (2015-NOW)

Developed MAC OS X application for use in Video Production Studios. Used SWIFT programing language. Work on GUI design, underline logic and workflow. It was very tricky to make Xcode 6.4 project and make Interface Storyboard for using power of VLC framework. Framework is written in C and C++. I was in opportunity to figure out how VLC is working. and once again, to remember syntax for other programing language. Everything else, except VLC framework, is coded in SWIFT 1.2 totally, new controls, custom written parsers, code, animations.

Augmented Reality (2015-NOW)

Developed several in-house applications, that uses ability to show 3D objects and animations in real world. Used for several Business cases Used vuforia SDK and take deap in technology. Now I can produce highest quality apps using augmented reality.

VQuarter (2014-2015)

Work as System Architect, iOS developer, Designer, Project Manager. System is using several different technology's. Work and lead team of 8 developers. For iOS, I was able to produce a prototype in a short period of time (2 weeks - 18 screens with basic logic) to validate capability and then followed up with the final app (49 screens). Both apps are done in SWIFT. I was also working on GUI design, underline logic and workflow.

https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/vquarter/id951012702

Scandic Victoria Tower (2013-NOW)

Build a completely dynamic and very complex iPad and iPhone native application, BackOffice, with realtime update of every single part of the app. This is first clien of Smart Hotels Project. Here we implement three types of norifications (distance, local, APNS). Also add multi-language cashing mechanism.

https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/scandic-victoria-tower/id788653935

Dagens Industri (2013)

It's enterprise application only for internal use. I use lot of different libraries that I customize, so that can mach the final user impression. Integration of chat is done part from open source (as basic I use XMPPFramework) and the rest is written from scratch. Also I customized and correct lots of errors within framework modules. For the Quiz part of the app I used simple algorithms from memory game that I coded for desktop.

Hogis - SÄLENS HÖGFJÄLLSHOTELL (2013)

I worked with the native framework on REST integration. By using it, I accomplish web service integration much simpler but I did have to code some complex dynamic mappings. Worked on some subtle, grouped animations for purchases. https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/hogis/id787433478



curriculum vitae

Hägerstensvägen 175, 126 53 Stockholm, Sweden +46 70 092 30 27 sasha.milic@mac.com

INDIVIDUAL PROJECTS: VoiP application (2014-2015)

Build complete system for VoiP application. Connection with telecommunication company iOS, API, cashing.... viber + multiple features in one.

GastroSuisse (2014)

My focus was in parsing whole pages and make navigation menu as separate part of application. The key solution was to paste link structure on advice and change in realtime all links so the web shell app can work without internet connection. https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/gastrosuisse/id926013771

Bugelhof - Hotel Bügelhof, Sälen (2014)

Hotel system for managing the ski resort with dynamic managing of notifications, information's, food and drink menu. Used technologies Objective-C and CMS. https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/bugelhof/id787472172

ExtraDeal (2013-2015)

This is system like Groupon website. Work on development iOS webshell application. Add notification (APN), parse HTML and rearrange code so it could be more like to native app. Storing cookies from webshell to be able to do autologin. https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/extradeal/id721769613

Farmen - Förlängda Armen (2013-2015)

Application code in Objective-C. Standard shell application with support of native PayPal payment processor. Login is done as sending unique ID from each phone and connect it to user and payment plan. API communication in basic functions. Everything else is loaded over WebViewController.

Education

UNIVERSITY: UNIVERSITY OF MATHEMATICS AND NATURAL SCIENCE

(1995-1999)

Graduate studies at the Institute of Mathematics and Informatics for obtaining the title of mathematician with average points: 8.92 of 10

SCHOOL: ELECTRO-TECHNIC SCHOOL "GOSA", S.PALANKA (1990-1994)

https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/farmen/id689931791

Electrical and automation techniques from computer science

Final exam score: Excellent (A)

CURRENTLY STUDYING (online): ACADEMY OF ART UNIVERSITY, CALIFONIA, USA (2011-NOW)

School of Animation & Visual Effects Master of Fine Arts (MFA)

Skills & Interests

LANGUAGES: English (A), French (B+), Deutsch (D)

Ability to quickly learn any language. Start to learn Swedish.

IT SKILLS: TIME IS PRECIOUS (1981-NOW)

On next page is the list of skills and years of experience in different branches of IT.



curriculum vitae

Hägerstensvägen 175, 126 53 Stockholm, Sweden +46 70 092 30 27 sasha.milic@mac.com

PROGRAM LANGUAGES:

SKILL SETS	YEAR OF EXPERIENCE	SKILL LEVEL	LAST USED
SWIFT	2	• • • •	present
Objective-C	6	• • • • •	present
C++ / C#	4	• • • • •	2012
Asembler / Low level	4	• • • • •	2010
PHP-HTML5-CSS3-JavaScript	13	• • • • •	present
MAYA Embeded language (MEL)	3	• • • •	present

Frameworks and SDK:

SKILL SETS			
Augmented Reality - Vuforia SDK	AddressBookUI		
NSObject-ObjectMap	Push Notification APN		
XMLDictionary	Core Animation		
MailComposer	Core Graphics		
VLC for MAC framework	Core Location		
PayPalMobile SDK	MessageUI		
libPods-JBChartView	MapKit		
AddressBookUI	QuartzCore		
AVFoundation	Custom API integration		
SystemConfiguration	JSON parser		
Facebook SDK	Customise iCarousel		
Tweeter SDK	Unity SDK		
iBeacon Kit	HomeKit		
Game Center	WebKit		
High Resolution	HTTP Live Streaming		
Metal	AirPrint		
OpenGL OpenGL ES	iBooks		
SceneKit	SpriteKit		

SOFTWARE:

SKILL SETS	YEAR OF EXPERIENCE	SKILL LEVEL		LAST USED
XCode / Instruments	9	• • • •	•	present
PaintCode v.XX	4	• • • •	•	present
Paw ultimate REST client for MAC	4	• • • •	•	present
Pusher - everything needed for APN	5	• • • •	•	present
Calabash - Auto. acceptance testing	3	• • • •	•	present
Adobe Complete Pack of programs	22	• • • •	•	present
AutoDesk MAYA v.XX	12	• • • •	•	present
Mudbox & ZBrush Sculpting programs	11	• • • •	•	2014
WEB development programs	19	• • • •	•	present
Animation and Post-production progra	ms 14	• • • •	•	2012
JIRA / BitBicket / GitHub / Scrum	6	• • • •	•	present
RealTimeBoard	5	• • • •	•	present



Hägerstensvägen 175, 126 53 Stockholm, Sweden +46 70 092 30 27 ⊌ sasha.milic@mac.com

SKILLS:

I make it my goal to create software with the user in mind, creating applications with a useable and intuitive user interface experience. I also understand the importance of creating highly readable and easily maintainable source code. I am constantly striving to learn new technologies and look for ways to better myself in this rapidly changing industry.

Usually, I am responsible for all, employers and clients, managing the projects, getting people together to turning ideas to reality. I worked for many Swedish companys doing projects for web, mobile, desktop and education and commercial business.

Proficient with advanced iOS technologies including Core Data, Core Location, MapKit, Grand Central Dispatch, and Auto Layout. Strong self learner with a desire to stay highly informed on best practices and latest developments to Apple's iOS mobile platform.

As an iOS, Android and MAC team leader I was also developing concepts and hardware products across various categories, vendors and markets. I was interacting with the global portfolio team and innovation team.

Ability to analyze extremely complex client requirements and recommend sophisticated development or acquisition strategies. Assist client in developing strategic plans and concepts. Advise clients on the impact of new legislation and emerging technologies that are relevant to their activity.

Provide technical experience in highly specialized technical and professional areas, on an enterprise-wide scale. Best practices I have for enterprise-size clients.

Specific experience with new and / or leading edge technologies and the deployment of these solutions to enterprise organizations.

Work without technical oversight and to lead and/or supervise a team of specialists. Superior oral and written communications skills in order to clearly and effectively convey issues, reports, and other deliverables in English, French and Serbian. Just start to learn Swedish.

OTHER SKILLS AND INTERESTS:

I enjoy **graphic** and **UI design**, for both digital and print services, which lead me to pursue an online business in supplying my creativity and knowledge to cutomers.

I also enjoy **photography** but **painting** and **schaching** is my first love. Another hobby of mine is playing **basketball** and tranning **karate**.

Love mathematics, quantum phisics, hardware and software inovations.

Interested in history, nature and psychology.

Why me?

FLEXIBLE: MY FIRST PRINCIPE IS TO LIVE CLOSE TO PLACE WHERE I WORK

I don't have problem in moving to other locations. Ability to easy adobt the way of living in different countries. Ability to quickly learn languages. Work on-line is no problem. Different time zone also is not the problem.

IN SHORT: GOOD DESIGN EMBODIES A MAGNANIMOUS VISION BASED ON TALENT,

EMPATHY, AND A GENUINE DESIRE TO SOLVE PROBLEMS WITH HEART,

RIGOR AND SKILL